[rock 'n' roll music playing]
[engine revving]
[tires screeching]
[Jerry] This is a 1970
Plymouth Road Runner Superbird.
Listen to all these great words
that describe it.
[engine revving]
A 440-cubic inch six pack
with three Holley two-barrel carbs.
What is that? You don't know,
but it sounds fantastic.
[upbeat music playing]
It's got Mopar's legendary
TorqueFlite 727 automatic
with a 355 rear end.
The front nose cone
adds 19 inches to the overall length,
and the rear wing stands five feet tall.
Okay, so the story
with this crazy thing is
Plymouth built this to try and convince
Richard Petty, the famous race car driver,
to race for them in 1970.
He saw the car and went, "I'm in."
These cars could go over 200 miles an hour
and won tons of races.
[jazz music playing]
I remember as a kid seeing the
Road Runner cartoon character on the side
and thinking, "This is fun, this is crazy.
What other car is based
on a cartoon character?"
It's happy, it's silly.
Listen to the horn.
[beeps]
[Jerry] That's the Road Runner!
Which is why this is the perfect car
for my happy, fun, unbelievably hilarious
special guest today,
Mr. Will Ferrell.
[phone ringing]
-[Jerry] Will?
-[Will] Yeah?
-It's Jerry.
-[Will] Of course.
[Jerry] Jerry is a comedy name.
Whereas, your first name
just comes to a dead stop.
[Will] Otherwise, it's a juxtaposition.
"How could that guy be funny?
His name's Will."
[Jerry] I think that's your whole career,
if I may sum it up.
-You just don't act like you look.
-[Will] Yep, that's it.
[Jerry]
You have worked the hell outta that.
[Will] You've nailed it.
-Where do I pick you up?
-Pick me up... I'm at the park.
[Jerry] The park? What kind of park?
[Will] You'll see me.
I'll be on the swing set.
Hi, I'm Jerry Seinfeld, and this is
Comedians in Cars Getting Coffee.
[car honks]
-[Jerry] Hey, little boy.
-[Will] Hey.
You like candy?
Yeah. I'm getting out of here.
[slow music playing]
I had a school interview
with my oldest boy today.
-Really?
-Yeah.
He's in sixth grade.
-He's such a good politician.
-Really?
Oh, he will talk about,
"I like the inclusive nature
of your school."
I'm like, "Who is this kid?"
"I like what your mission statement says."
[laughing]
Which... In sixth grade,
I wasn't saying things like that.
-No.
-Yeah.
[inaudible]
I should've had, like, a cigar,
that I keep ignoring them when they say,
"You can't smoke in here."
"Oh, I didn't hear you."
And then, let 30 seconds pass, and then...
"So, what kind of sports teams
do you have here?"
"Mr. Ferrell, I'm gonna ask you
for the last time to put the cigar out."
[upbeat music playing]
-[Will] This is great.
-[Jerry] Fun, right?
-Cars don't smell like this anymore.
-[Jerry] No.
They don't look like this
or feel like this.
[Will] Did you know that
this is my color too?
-I love this color blue.
-You're kidding.
Let's do the scale of pretentious
of these words.
-Film, picture, movie.
-Oh.
Most pretentious, "picture."
"It's a wonderful picture."
It's very self-consciously hip, I think,
-to call it a picture.
-"Film" is close second.
"Film" is close second.
And "movie" is undeniably
the least pretentious.
Yeah, you're right. You're right.
Why do people in movies, film,
or pictures...
-Right.
-...think they're very, very important?
I don't know, but I love it so much.
[Jerry] Why the full names of the actors?
Bradley Cooper.
No one's calling him "Bradley"
in his life, come on.
-Robert De Niro.
But no one's calling him "Robert."
-He's Bob.
-Right.
-Everybody knows.
-I don't know him.
-Yeah. Right.
He's gotta be Bob.
[Jerry] What movies have you seen lately?
-I don't see a lot of things.
-You don't?
-I gotta be honest.
-Why?
I don't know.
In fact, name a movie,
and I bet you I haven't seen it.
-Whiplash.
-No.
-Fruitvale Station.
Tom Hanks in the hijack boat movie.
-Captain Phillips.
-Never saw it.
-Are you kidding?
I am serious.
Gravity. Yes.
-No.
-Get out.
I haven't seen it.
That's great.
I would love to be the one guy
that didn't see Gravity.
I... [laughs]
I was there
the night you opened the Irvine Improv.
What year would that have been?
-Do you recall?
-'85?
-Four?
-I would've been still in high school.
-Really?
-Yeah.
Yeah, I remember your joke about
the moose getting picked up.
-Yes.
-And the moose is like...
Right. It was a moose that got rescued
-from an island.
-Right.
They picked him up with a helicopter.
-And you were wondering--
-He was in a harness and he was floating
and he's in midair.
The line was,
"Well, I guess I can fly now."
[laughs]
-This is the California you gotta love.
-So nice.
-This is what you dream about.
-Yeah.
[surfer music playing]
-L.A. beaches are so beautiful.
-Until it rains.
And then all the sewage dumps out there.
Could you explain...
Welcome.
[Jerry] You know, I've heard this.
I have a vague understanding of,
-when it rains, what happens?
-Yeah.
[Will] So, L.A. was built in such a way
that the treatment facilities overflow.
And it flows out into
the Santa Monica Bay.
[both laughing]
Hungry?
[jazz music playing]
-He's gonna have--
-Do you have--
-I'm gonna have decaf.
-Okay.
And I'll have regular.
Can I get you guys anything to drink?
-[Will] Oh.
-Uh...
-[stammers] I think decaf coffee?
-Could we...
Yeah? Decaf and a regular?
-Yeah. Thank you.
-Okay. Sounds good.
-Was that...
-That was a test.
I like a place with
a lot of items on the menu
'cause you know
they do them all beautifully.
-What do you weigh now?
-I'm like 218.
Sometimes I'm like... I do think,
"For the amount that I'm working out,
why am I not losing weight?"
What would you like to look like?
[sighs]
-My dream would be 200.
-Is that sensitive? Am I--
-Two hundred?
-But you know what the sad...
I have to work out just to look fat.
That's the problem.
If I took my shirt off, you'd go,
"Ooh, not so good."
That's why we have shirts.
[guitar music playing]
I was a bank teller for a little while.
-In real life?
-In real life.
I would recruit people at the bank
to come see my stand-up comedy
'cause I had a little moment
-of trying stand-up.
-Right.
And I remember one manager saw a flyer
that I put up in the break room
and she was like, "You do comedy?
I'd like to see that."
And just walked out.
Translation, "No way is that guy funny.
There's no way."
I had found a stand-up comedy workshop,
a junior college adult-ed,
like Irvine Valley extension course.
And it was a six-week class.
-"Learn how to be a stand-up comedian."
-Right.
It was literally just a guy with
a Peavey amp and a microphone
in a junior high classroom,
and he would just stand up there.
In the first class were 30 people,
and by the second class,
there were 15 people,
and by the third class,
there were seven of us.
Tell me how you came up...
Did you have a cat? The cat bit
from your audition for SNL.
No, I didn't have one.
-Come on.
-Yeah.
Girlfriend had one?
-No, I just watched cats.
-Come on!
[Will] That's a harrowing moment.
We had to do our auditions at 8H,
you know, the studio
-where they do the show.
-Right.
But he had you do it to an empty...
There's no one in... There's no audience.
So, I'm rolling around playing with
cat toys to dead silence thinking,
"This is the end. This is it."
With just the television camera
and the sound guy...
[giggling] Right.
-...wondering when his lunch break is.
-Yeah.
And I'm rolling around with cat toys.
But I thought,
"There's no turning back now."
Now, I'm watching this,
whatever years later, going...
-Right.
-..."My God. You got him with the cat bit.
This guy just became a star
'cause he had a cat bit."
Thank you very much.
[Will] I wrote that at the Groundlings.
Just a guy who would go
over in the corner
and play with cat toys
while we're having a dinner party.
The other guests are like,
"What is he doing?"
It's like, "It's just something he does.
Anyway, so,
-we're trying to get Tommy into school--"
-That's really great.
And I'd just be over there...
Then I walk over to her
at a certain point.
She'd bring the feather on the stick
and she'd just keep talking
and I'd play with it. Yeah.
[Jerry] We have a cat now.
I gave it to my wife for Mother's Day
'cause I thought,
-"One time in life--"
-Did she want a cat?
She had mentioned it and I would say,
"Absolutely not. I don't want that."
And I thought, "One time in life, I wanna
give someone a box with a kitten in it."
-Right? One time.
-Sure.
And she'd feel it
and she feels something moving around.
You know, and it's not a real box.
You know, it's a TV type box.
It opens, and the cat jumped out.
-And did it...
-It was fantastic.
-Great.
-And this cat
is fascinated by mechanical things.
So, the cat is constantly on the phone
in the house.
You'd go in the room
and you see the phone--
-A speaker phone?
-And then start playing with it,
start hitting the buttons, and we'd joke,
"He's trying to reach another cat."
[mimics dialing]
And I say to him,
"Don't play with the phone anymore.
Stop playing with the phone."
-And does he even look at you?
-Yeah.
Is there anything more futile
than telling a cat
-what you don't want it to do?
-There's no-- Totally.
-"Don't do that."
-It would never listen to you.
His name is Javier.
I say, "Javi, don't do that
with the phone. It's annoying."
And he probably just goes...
"I gotta go right back to it."
They will play with something,
and then totally lose interest.
Look at something.
Like they're... Like, "Remember that time
I was looking for that one thing?
God, did I...
Anyway."
Then go right back to...
But they have daydream moments. Yeah.
"Remember that time I was
looking for that one thing?"
218. Jesus.
I'm just kidding.
I think I even lied.
It's more like 220.
"Good Lord, 218?"
Good Lord.
Okay, okay.
Wow.
I always feel very strange when
someone refers to what we do as art.
Anything that you make out of thin air
-that someone else likes is art.
-Yeah.
My wife showed me this painting
the other day that she wanted to buy.
-It's a picture of a bunny, okay?
-Right.
It's a picture of a bunny.
I don't care how great it is,
and it is great, and the guy is great,
and it's great, and I'm sure
it's worth every penny.
-It's still a picture of a bunny.
-Yeah.
What did he do? Tell me what he did?
I'll tell you what he did.
He said, "I think I'm gonna make
this great picture of a bunny.
It's gonna be so great,
people are gonna go nuts for it."
And he did it.
Right.
Then I said, "I'd like to meet this guy."
-He lives in New York.
-Okay.
So, they call the person and they go,
"He doesn't meet with people."
-He's an artist. Doesn't meet with people.
-Right.
'Cause he's got no defense either
for the fact that it's
-this much money for a picture of a bunny.
-Totally.
He's afraid I might say,
-"It's just a bunny. Come on."
-"It's a picture of a bunny."
"I know."
"Right?"
-"Thank you for your visit."
-"Yes. Let me get back in my..."
What about this guy?
[jazz music playing]
I love Greek food.
-Are you in Greece a lot?
-Mmm-hmm.
-Are you really? Oh.
-Yeah.
Well, touché.
I thought I was being really funny.
You were like, "No, I'm there."
-"I love it there, in fact."
-I do.
Were you there last year?
This year.
-And how was it with all the...
-Fantastic.
-...chaos and all that?
-It's great.
-They don't care?
-Don't care.
We don't care, they don't care.
Nobody cares.
You think that affects the baklava
in any way?
-Delicious. Come on.
-It's delicious.
Olives, the feta cheese,
it's all the same.
I love how the Greeks are like,
"Okay, give us some more money,
we're really gonna buckle down."
There's two more people in the café.
[Jerry] They look like they're
gonna eat something?
-I don't think so.
-Oh, damn it.
God damn it.
This café, it's like Greece.
There's no real visible
financial model here that makes any sense.
But they'll be open tomorrow.
Right. Right.
And olives and falafel and baklava
will be here available.
-"And we hope you come back."
-Yeah.
-"And if you don't--"
-No problem.
-"We'd love to see you."
-Yeah.
"But if you can't make it, we get it."
What does your wife
get upset with you about?
What do you do that she gets upset?
-Behaviorally?
-What about social situations?
If it's in some arena
that's very important to her,
and I were to start to...
-Go off?
-...go off,
she may say something to me in Swedish.
-Your wife is Swedish.
-Right.
That's our... She'll be like,
"Okay, sluta. Sluta now."
Which is, "Stop now."
This was a good interview.
Anyway, goes without saying,
I would love to work here.
I want to reiterate, I think
my only weakness is that I try too hard.
Mm-hmm. [laughs]
-I don't really have a business.
-Yeah.
-Oh.
-I just like to put out ads, see--
-See who responds. Etcetera.
-Yeah.
-So, there's really not even a job.
-There's nothing.
No, no, there's nothing.
I hope that's okay.
I hope that you didn't feel like
-you wasted your time.
-No--
In the bottom, it says,
"Not a real company."
Okay. Okay.
You know what, that's my fault.
I didn't read the thing close enough.
-[funky music playing]
-[inaudible]
Don't act like you're not Will Ferrell.
-Oh, I'm acting like...
-[laughing]
Will you be involved
in the edit of this new movie?
I'll go to the preview,
but I can't sit through the, uh...
-Focus group?
-Focus group.
-I can't sit through that because--
-Pretty rough.
But then you'll hear something
that's like,
"What were some of your other
impressions about the movie?
Okay, so you liked... Oh, you liked it...
John over here, he liked it
when Will put the funny hat on.
Then you-- Show of hands.
How many people liked
when Will put on the funny hat?
Sixteen out of 20."
But then, they inevitably go...
They go positive, and they go,
"And what did you not like
about the movie?"
Which then becomes, naturally,
a feeding frenzy.
'Cause you're not just gonna
sit there and go, "I'm good,"
'cause then you start going,
"Well, actually, I didn't like this."
And that'll turn... Someone else will go,
"Yeah, I hated that, too."
-It's the children's entertainer eye-wipe.
-Yeah.
"Oh, you hated that part."
"I usually don't like
Will Ferrell in movies,
but this one, it was not bad.
He usually gets on my nerves,
but this one, you know,
thought he was pretty good."
[funky music playing]
Jerry, scale of one to ten,
-ten being you just love...
-I know the scale of one to ten, okay?
...you just love driving the Road Runner.
-One... Eh. Okay.
-Yeah, I know the scale.
-Okay. Okay.
-Okay?
All right? Everybody knows the scale.
-I'm just asking.
-Everybody.
-You know, it's irritating.
-Honestly, it's my job.
I know the ten to one scale.
How would you classify your experience...
Talking to you? Zero.
-...talking to me right now?
-It's a zero.
Zero? We'll put you down as one.
"No, I said 'zero.'"
Because you're just leading me
to make judgments about everything
and it's annoying.
Okay?
Okay. Interesting. Interesting.
So, you don't--
Okay, so you don't enjoy
my presence at all.
-At all. No.
-Okay.
If I could murder you now, I would.
-Okay?
-Okay.
All right. So you would
end my life if you could.
-That's right. Right here, right now.
-Okay, right here. Okay.
I would choke you out.
Do you remember that I am the one
who told you to just--
-Yes. "Just marry."
-Just get married.
-You were dating your wife.
-Yeah. "Just get married."
-I said, "Just get married."
-"Just do it."
-And you did it.
-Yeah.
I followed your advice.
-We didn't even know each other.
-No.
And you just said it.
It's been the best decision.
-I was right.
-You were right.
I think.